<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wonder&#39;s Lab</title>
    <link>https://wonderfall.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wonder&#39;s Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 21:23:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wonderfall.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker &amp; OCI: a humble hardening guide</title>
      <link>https://wonderfall.dev/docker-hardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 21:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wonderfall.dev/docker-hardening/</guid>
      <description>Containers aren&amp;rsquo;t that new fancy thing anymore, but they were a big deal. And they still are. They are a concrete solution to the following problem:
 - Hey, your software doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&amp;hellip;
  - Sorry, it works on my computer! Can&amp;rsquo;t help you.
 Whether we like them or not, containers are here to stay. Their expressiveness and semantics allow for an abstraction of the OS dependencies that a software has, the latter being often dynamically linked against certain libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F-Droid: how is it weakening the Android security model?</title>
      <link>https://wonderfall.dev/fdroid-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 21:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wonderfall.dev/fdroid-issues/</guid>
      <description>F-Droid is a popular alternative app repository for Android, especially known for its main repository dedicated to free and open-source software. F-Droid is often recommended among security and privacy enthusiasts, but how does it stack up against Play Store in practice? This write-up will attempt to emphasize major security issues with F-Droid that you should consider.
Before we start, a few things to keep in mind:
 The main goal of this write-up was to inform users so they can make responsible choices, not to trash someone else&amp;rsquo;s work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wonderfall.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wonderfall.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>You may call me &amp;ldquo;Wonderfall&amp;rdquo;. I was young and it sounded cool.
$ whoami I&amp;#39;m just a random guy passing by on the Internet who is interested in all kinds of things. And as you can tell, I&amp;#39;m a nerd. $ ls -l content/ technology security privacy rants photography pharmacology medicine science $ git config --get remote.origin.url https://github.com/Wonderfall/wonderfall.github.io </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
